Okay, so I've made one small change and
that is I've changed the unordered list
to an ordered list. So now I can say go
shopping
and add an item. And then I can say go
uh go to the bank and add an item. Well,
you'll notice that appending the item to
the end makes it so that it is number
two in the list. And maybe I need it to
go to the bank before I go shopping. So,
it' be nice to instead of inserting at
the end, um it'd be nice to insert
before. So, let's come over here. I've
added a new button called insert item.
Insert item. I want it to put at the top
of the list the new item. So, we can
actually take a lot of stuff from add
item and copy it into insert item. So, I
still want to gather the input. I still
want to create a new element. I still
want to set the elements inner text or
sorry text content equal to whatever the
user typed into the box and I want to
still access the output but I want to
put it in a specific spot rather than
just appending it to the end. I want it
in a specific spot. Well to do that we
need to find the element that we want to
put it before. Um because instead of
doing append child you'll sayinsert
before. Insert before takes two things.
It takes the thing you want to insert
and it takes the thing you're supposed
to insert it before. So first you say go
to the document, find this element that
has the ID of output. So it comes up
here and finds this. And then it says in
there I want you to insert a tag and I
want you to insert it before something.
Well, insert before um
takes in two elements. So we need to
find an element that's inside of output.
So the way we do that is we say document
doquery selector and it um either
returns an HTML element or it returns
nothing or null. Insert before will
either insert this element that we're
trying to insert before the element that
we found or if it gets a null it'll
insert it as the last item in the list
because it'll be the only item in the
list. So, we're going to do document
query selector and we are going to look
for list items. Query selector finds the
very first list item that matches. We
could do query selector all to grab all
of the list items, but in this case, I
want to insert it first, which means I
want to insert it before the first list
item. And in fact, we can actually
narrow our search by saying, let's look
in the output tag for a list item that's
immediately inside of it. So, it's going
to come up here to this
output tag and it's going to see if
there are any list items. If there are,
it will return the list item, the very
first one in this list. If there aren't,
it will return null. So, let's put that
in a variable to access it. So, we'll
say let first li equal document.query
selector. So, we've now found our first
list item. Now we're going to find the
output tag, insert into the output tag,
and we want to insert our new line item
that we've created. So we'll say insert
my list item. And where do we want to
insert it before? Well, we want to
insert it before the first list item.
So if we save this and we come over
here, we can say go shopping,
add the item and then we can say go to
the bank and insert the item and it
inserts it above, shifts the other one
down, and now this one is one and this
one is two. And reloading it, there is
no list items right now. So it should
return null. So if we say go choose a
bank and insert item because it was null
it just added our item at the very end
of the ul tag. And that concludes how
you would use insert